{
    "isTheory": true,
    "openingRemarks": "Finding Factors of Integers with A Given Sum",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is -5 and whose sum is 4.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing -5 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to 4.\n<p>The possible factorizations of -5 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p> -1 &times; 5\n<p>1 &times; -5\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>-1 + 5 = 4 (this is the desired result)\n<p>1 + -5 = -4\n<p>So the two integers whose product is -5 and whose sum is 4, are <strong>-1</strong> and <strong>5</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is 6 and whose sum is -5.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing 6 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to -5.\n<p>The possible factorizations of 6 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>1 &times; 6\n<p>-1 &times; -6<p>2 &times; 3<p>-2 &times; -3\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>1 + 6 = 7\n<p>-1 + -6 = -7\n<p>2 + 3 = 5\n<p>-2 + -3 = -5 (this is the desired result)\n<p>So the two integers whose product is 6 and whose sum is -5, are <strong>-2</strong> and <strong>-3</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is -15 and whose sum is 8.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing -15 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to 8.\n<p>The possible factorizations of -15 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>-1 &times; 15\n<p>1 &times; -15<p>-3 &times; 5<p>3 &times; -5\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>-1 + 15 = 14\n<p>1 + -15 = -14\n<p>-3 + 5 = 2\n<p>3 + -5 = -2\n<p>Since none of the sums is 8, then <em>there are no two integers whose product is -15 and whose sum is 8</em>."
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is 18 and whose sum is 9.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing 18 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to 9.\n<p>The possible factorizations of 18 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>1 &times; 18\n<p>-1 &times; -18<p>2 &times; 9<p>-2 &times; -9<p>3 &times; 6<p>-3 &times; -6\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>1 + 18 = 19\n<p>-1 + -18 = -19\n<p>2 + 9 = 11\n<p>-2 + -9 = -11\n<p>3 + 6 = 9 (this is the desired result)\n<p>-3 + -6 = -9\n<p>So the two integers whose product is 18 and whose sum is 9, are <strong>3</strong> and <strong>6</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is -24 and whose sum is -10.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing -24 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to -10.\n<p>The possible factorizations of -24 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>-1 &times; 24\n<p>1 &times; -24<p>-2 &times; 12<p>2 &times; -12<p>-3 &times; 8<p>3 &times; -8<p>-4 &times; 6<p>4 &times; -6\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>-1 + 24 = 23\n<p>1 + -24 = -23<p>-2 + 12 = 10<p>2 + -12 = -10 (this is the desired result)\n<p>-3 + 8 = 5<p>3 + -8 = -5<p>-4 + 6 = 2<p>4 + -6 = -2\n<p>So the two integers whose product is -24 and whose sum is -10, are <strong>2</strong> and <strong>-12</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is 25 and whose sum is -10.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing 25 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to -10.\n<p>The possible factorizations of 25 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>1 &times; 25\n<p>-1 &times; -25<p>5 &times; 5<p>-5 &times; -5\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>1 + 25 = 26\n<p>-1 + -25 = -26<p>5 + 5 = 10<p>-5 + -5 = -10 (this is the desired result)\n<p>So the two integers whose product is 25 and whose sum is -10, are <strong>-5</strong> and <strong>-5</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is -27 and whose sum is -40.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing -27 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to -40.\n<p>The possible factorizations of -27 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>-1 &times; 27\n<p>1 &times; -27<p>-3 &times; 9<p>3 &times; -9\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>-1 + 27 = 26\n<p>1 + -27 = -26\n<p>-3 + 9 = 6\n<p>3 + -9 = -6\n<p>Since none of the sums is -40, then <em>there are no two integers whose product is -27 and whose sum is -40</em>."
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is 28 and whose sum is 11.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing 28 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to 11.\n<p>The possible factorizations of 28 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>1 &times; 28\n<p>-1 &times; -28<p>2 &times; 14\n<p>-2 &times; -14\n<p>4 &times; 7\n<p>-4 &times; -7\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>1 + 28 = 29\n<p>-1 + -28 = -29<p>2 + 14 = 16\n<p>-2 + -14 = -16\n<p>4 + 7 = 11 (this is the desired result)\n<p>-4 + -7 = -11\n<p>So the two integers whose product is 28 and whose sum is 11, are <strong>4</strong> and <strong>7</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is -29 and whose sum is 28.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing -29 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to 28.\n<p>The possible factorizations of -29 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p> -1 &times; 29\n<p>1 &times; -29\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>-1 + 29 = 28 (this is the desired result)\n<p>1 + -29 = -28\n<p>So the two integers whose product is -29 and whose sum is 28, are <strong>-1</strong> and <strong>29</strong>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Find two integers whose product is 30 and whose sum is 28.",
            "answer": "<p>Start by factorizing 30 into all possible product expressions of two integers, and then select the factor pair (if any) which sum up to 28.\n<p>The possible factorizations of 30 into product of two integers can be determined to be:\n<p>1 &times; 30\n<p>-1 &times; -30<p>2 &times; 15\n<p>-2 &times; -15\n<p>3 &times; 10\n<p>-3 &times; -10\n<p>5 &times; 6\n<p>-5 &times; -6\n<p>And the sums of the factors in each factorization are as follows:\n<p>1 + 30 = 31\n<p>-1 + -30 = -31<p>2 + 15 = 17\n<p>-2 + -15 = -17\n<p>3 + 10 = 13\n<p>-3 + -10 = -13\n<p>5 + 6 = 11\n<p>-5 + -6 = -11\n<p>Since none of the sums is 28, then <em>there are no two integers whose product is 30 and whose sum is 28</em>."
        }
    ]
}